卸了轮子 拿了钱就走
We get the wheels, we get la Feria,
别捅娄子
we keep moving on. No messing around.
这次再把轮子搞坏
You mess those wheels up this time, Chong,
我一定要你们好看
I'm gonna have your ass.
快 动手
Move!
- 去那边 伙计  - 都没吃饭吗
- Right there, homes.  - There's nobody, homes.
你是来开派对的吗
Where's your party, boy?
把收音机关掉
Turn down the radio.
你想把警察引来还是想怎样
You inviting the cops, too, or what?
我要些铬
I want el Cromó.
看来这次
Gonna get some green
能赚不少钱 伙计们
for this shit right here, homes.
见鬼
Fuck.
伙计们
Uh, guys?
这些螺帽全是镀铬的 都被你们磨坏了
Those are chrome-plated lugs. You're gonna strip them.
看看这家伙
Look at this guy, eh?
镀层都被你们刮花了
The plating flakes off.
是吗？
Yeah?
这车是租来的 没人会花钱开一辆...
This is a lease. No one's gonna pay to ride...
找死 继续干活儿
该死
Shit.
快点
Come on, man.
伙计们 伙计们
Uh, guys, guys.
怎么会
What the fuck?
伙计们 说真的 你们会后悔的
Guys, seriously, you don't wanna do this.
摆平他
Take him out.
打死他
Fuck him up!
不 别朝车开枪
No! Not the car!
打死这个基佬
Get that puto!
打死他
Fuck him up, man!
Fuck him up!
打他
Get him!
往死里打
Hit that fool!
混蛋
Motherfucker!
该死
Shit.
见鬼
Fuck.
所有人都睡了 伯特
Everyone's asleep, Burt.
或者在梦游 就像冰川融化
Sleepwalking. Between the ice caps,
色情小说作家 有毒的水源 变种人
the pornographers, poisoned water, mutants...
其实他们都有联系
it's all connected.
嘿 克莱德 都已经2029年了
Hey, Clyde. It's 2029.
为什么我们还要提起变种人
Why are we still talking about mutants?
是我 我在车上
Hey, it's me. I'm in the car.
对 旅途很愉快
Yeah, it was a good trip.
干完就走人
Killed it up and down the fence.
美利坚 美利坚 美利坚
USA! USA! USA!
USA! USA! USA! USA!
金刚狼
Wolverine.
我知道是你
I knew it was you.
- 见鬼  - 请别走
- Oh, fuck.  - Please!
我有事相求
I'm in trouble!
你是唯一能帮我们的人
You're the only one that could help!
我需要像你这样的英雄
有多远给我滚多远
Get the fuck away from me!
你到底经历了什么？
为什么要躲起来
求你了
Please!
罗根
Logan!
那人是谁
Who was that?
不知道哪儿来的疯女人 不必担心
I don't know, some crazy lady. Don't worry.
真是百闻不如一见 金刚狼
As I live and breathe, the Wolverine.
可惜他成了瘾君子
And he's a junkie now.
你又是谁
Who the fuck are you?
你车门上怎么有弹孔啊
You know, you got some buckshot in your door.
我听说你在凤凰城
I heard you was in Phoenix.
可昨晚我德州的朋友
But then, last night, some friends of mine
打来电话
in Texas HP called...
说在54号公路旁的
and told me they found
水塘里发现3具墨西哥人的尸体
three dead cholos in a pullout on 54.
很平常 对吧
Not unusual, I know.
不过有具少只手 还有具少只腿
Except one was missing a hand, another one a leg.
这让他们觉得
So they was thinking...
可能是脱逃的老虎 或者《猛鬼街》里的佛瑞迪干的
it was either an escaped tiger or Freddy Krueger.
可是他们不可能会开车啊
But neither one of them can drive...
一个是电影虚构的 另一个已经灭绝了
one being fictional, the other one extinct.
而且他们找到的车轮防滑钉
And since the wheel lugs they found
是克莱斯勒上的
belonged to a '24 Chrysler...
刚好
and, well...
你开的就是克莱斯勒
this is a '24 Chrysler.
她找到你了吗
She found you yet?
加芙列拉
Gabriela?
听着
See...
我要找的不是你 狼叔
I'm not looking for you, Wolvie.
确切的说我要找的人
Well, not really. I'm looking for someone
恰巧在找你
who's looking for you.
她趁我不注意时带走了我的一样东西
She took something of mine when I wasn't looking.
一样我要担责任的东西
Something for which I am responsible.
一个墨西哥女人
Mexican lady.
她正在找你
Has her sights on you now.
没想起什么吗
Doesn't ring any bells?
我不认识什么加芙列拉 所以赶紧给我滚
I don't know any Gabriela, so get the fuck out of my car.
知道吗
You know...
我知道你把谁藏了起来 朋友
I know what you're hiding, amigo.
你把老光头藏在了墨西哥边境
The old cue ball south of the border.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
我只想你合作
A little co-operation.
差点忘了 你是我的偶像
I'm a fan, by the way.
阿尔卡利 基因改造研究所
安全部主任 唐纳德·皮尔斯
该死 该死
Fuck, fuck!
不 爱斯佩兰萨先生 不
No, Mr. Esperanza, no.
是说好六月 可我现在就需要那艘船
I know I said June, but I need the boat now.
为什么这样就得涨价
Why would that mean the price go up?
听着
Listen to me.
我知道你想要7万
I know you wanted 70...
好吧 如果我能一次性给你
Okay, what if I could put together
4万5现金呢
$45,000 cash right now?
喂 喂
Hello? Hello?
见鬼
Shit.
你即将离开美国境内
嘿 山姆
Hey, Sam.
早上好
Morning.
莎士比亚《尤利乌斯·凯撒》
我知道您有那样内心的美德 勃鲁托斯
"I know that virtue to be in you, Brutus.
正像我知道您的外貌一样
"As well as I do know your outward favor.
好 光荣正是我的谈话的题目
"Well, honor is the subject of my story."
他今天情况不太好
He's having a bad day.
哪天情况好过了
They're all bad days.
六个小时前他就该服药了
He needed these six hours ago.
你知道这些根本不够
This is not enough, you know.
一星期都撑不过
Won't see us through the week.
我会想办法的
I'm working on it.
轮到你了
Your turn.
我都折腾了一晚上了
I've had a rough night.
好吧 你可以的
Poor you.
还有件事 他昨晚和我说
In other news, he told me last night
他在和某个人神交
he's communicating with someone.
没人和他神交
He's not talking to anybody.
话别说那么绝对
Don't be so sure.
他还交代了很多细节
He's got all these details.
我还以为那个蓄水箱能把他隔绝起来
I thought that tank was supposed to act as a barrier.
- 可他发作起来根本不管用  - 求你消停会儿
- It's got them cracks in it.  - Just please stop.
左边下面
Bottom left.
你没在听我说话
You're not listening.
他又开始不停地问问题了 问为什么我们会在这儿
He's been asking questions again about why we're here.
我觉得他还想钻进我的意识里
I think he's trying to read my mind.
所以我们才要给他喂药
That's what these are for.
他正吃着奶油点心
Eating his curds and whey
然后一只大蜘蛛出现 坐在了她的旁边
Then came a big spider Which sat down beside her
吓了玛菲特小姐一跳
And frightened Miss Muffet...
朋友们 我有个好消息要告诉你们
Friends, I have good news for you today!
你们做什么并不重要
It's not about what you do.
做什么也不重要
It's not about your deeds.
你们只是无法按照
You can't live up to God's rules.
上帝的旨意而活 没关系 我们并非完人
He knows that you can't. It's okay, we're imperfect.
请让一下 先生
Make way, sir.
我说了让开
I said make way!
来自塔可钟快餐店的新墨西哥鸡肉卷
The new Quesalupa from Taco Bell!
加一份鸡肉 加一份牛排
Get it with chicken! Get it with steak!
还有包裹着浓郁芝士在火上慢烤的饼皮
And with the cheese baked right in the shell...
新一季的明星产品
it's the next big thing!
还不快来抢
Go now while supplies last.
你是谁
Who are you?
你知道我是谁
You know who I am.
你是那个总让我睡觉的家伙
You're the man who puts me to sleep.
我们都需要睡会儿
We both could use some sleep.
不 拿开 快拿开
No! No!
你想对我做什么
What are you doing to me?
查尔斯
Charles.
别这样
Come on, now.
我待在这儿多久了
How long have I been here?
这是什么
What are these?
你知道这是什么
You remember what they are.
打针可以缓解痉挛
The shots mellow the seizures.
按时吃药就不会发作了
The pills keep them from happening.
不如你吹口仙气 愿上帝保佑吧
How about you blow on them to make them safe?
去你的 罗根
Fuck off, Logan.
所以你想起来我是谁了
So you remember who I am now.
我一直都知道你是谁
I always know who you are.
只是有的时候没认出来而已
It's just sometimes I don't recognize you.
快吃药吧
Take the pills.
你把我一个人丢给那个有白化病的家伙
You leave me alone with that fucking albino.
他根本不听我说话
He doesn't listen to me.
我一看就知道他们是新的物种
I know a damn speciation when I see one.
什么
A what?
新的物种 新的变种人 很年轻
Speciation. New mutant, a young one.
有势力想要屠杀他们
There are forces trying to kill them.
- 势力  - 他们需要帮助
- Forces?  - They want help.
势力 势力
Forces, forces.
可惜你已经退出历史舞台了
It's too bad you're not in that business anymore.
他们需要的不是我 而是你
They don't want me, they want you.
好吧 他们还真是愚不可及
Oh, yes, that's how fucking stupid they are.
他们在自由女神像那儿等着你
They're waiting for you at the Statue of Liberty.
自由女神像早就没了
The Statue of Liberty was a long time ago,
查尔斯 都已经多少年了
Charles, a long time.
早就没有新的变种人了 明白吗
There are no new mutants. Understand?
已经有25年没有新的变种人出生了
Hasn't been a new one born in 25 years. Not anywhere.
你总是以为
You always thought...
我们是上帝计划的一部分
we were part of God's plan.
或许吧
But maybe...
又或者我们是上帝犯下的错误
Maybe we were God's mistake.
你太让我失望了
What a disappointment you are.
当年我找到你的时候
When I found you...
你还只是个做困兽之斗的拳手
you were pursuing a career as a cage fighter.
这对于杀手来说已经是个不错的归宿了
A warm capper to a life as an assassin.
靠嗑药为生
Hooked on barbiturates.
当时的你就是个野兽
You were an animal.
是我们接纳了你
But we took you in.
给了你一个温馨的家
I gave you a family.
可现在都没了
And they're gone now.
罗根
Logan.
Logan...
你到底做了什么
What did you do?
回答我 为什么我们会在这儿
Answer me! Why are we here?
这不是我该过的生活
No one should live like this.
在这破水箱里被药物麻痹
Drugged in a fucking tank!
- 这是为了你好  - 不 不对 这不是为了我好
- It's for your own good.  - No, it's not!
你只是在等我死
You're waiting for me to die.
我不想吵架
I don't wanna fight...
但有些事情总得商量着解决
but there's things we need to discuss.
什么事
What things?
好吧 你别嫌我唠叨
Well, would it be considered nagging...
我之前就已经和你说过了
if I was to repeat my previous observation...
这些剂量太少了 没法抑制他的痉挛
that the dose is too low to suppress the seizures?
那家伙就给我这些
It's what the guy gave me.
我没什么资格讨价还价
Wasn't in a position to make demands.
今早我差点就死在这儿了
I almost died this morning.
- 每次他一发作  - 连一分钟都没到
- That seizure was...  - It was barely a minute.
感觉根本不止一分钟 我都无法呼吸了
It felt a lot longer than a minute. I couldn't breathe.
你受到的影响比我小
You're less affected.
你知道该增加剂量了
You know he needs a higher dose.
我还知道你藏了不少钱
And I know you got more money squirreled away.
那些钱是用来带我们离开这里的
That money's to get us out of here.
不 不是我们 是你和他
No, not us. You and him.
你想买一艘“逐日号”游艇
You're saving to buy a Sunseeker.
“日”字是关键
"Sun" is the keyword.
我不觉得自己能像不死僵尸那样一辈子躲在船舱里
I hardly see myself cowering below decks like Nosferatu.
不是吗
Do you?
在那儿叠着你的短裤 给他做葡萄干布丁
Folding your underpants, and making him spotted dick.
在你口袋里找到的
Found this in your pocket.
艾德曼合金
Adamantium.
如果你想让自己的脑袋开花
If you are planning to blow your brains out...
请到了公海再动手吧
could you wait till you're out on the high seas?
- 我刚把地板拖干净  - 别和我说这些废话
- I just mopped these floors.  - I don't need this shit.
一年前 你找我来帮忙
A year ago, you asked me to help you.
我发誓我尽力了
And God knows I've tried.
可如果你不肯对我说出实情的话
But I can't help you, Logan, not really...
我想我没法帮到你
if you're not going to talk to me.
你晚上总是不睡觉 我能听见
I hear you at night. You're not sleeping.
你不想和我谈谈吗
You don't wanna talk about that.
还有你喝酒的事
Or the booze you're drinking.
还有手指间被你擦掉的脓水
Or the pus you're wiping away from your knuckles.
或者我洗衣服时看到的血迹
Or the blood I wash from your clothes.
又或者你胸口上的新伤口
Or the fresh wounds in your chest.
那些没有愈合的伤口
The ones that aren't healing.
以及我很肯定
And I'm pretty sure...
你已经看不清
you don't wanna talk about the fact
瓶子上的标签了
that you can't read the label on that bottle.
上面写的是布洛芬
It says, "Ibuprofen."
那是我最喜欢的马克杯
That was my favorite mug.
不用你多管闲事
Stay out of my shit.
我知道你出问题了 罗根
Something's happening to you, Logan.
在你的体内 你病了 我闻得出来
On the inside you're sick. I can smell it.
这是我最嗨的一晚
Best night ever!
司机大叔
Hey, driver.
我爱你 我也爱你
I love you. I love you.
你太可爱了
You're such a doll.
两名乘客 自由汽车旅馆
罗根先生
Mr. Logan.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
求你了 我们需要搭车
Please. We need a ride.
我没空 叫出租车吧
Not available. Call a cab.
我叫加芙列拉·洛佩兹
My name is Gabriela Lopez.
我不想知道 女士
I don't wanna know your name, lady.
有人在追杀我们
There are men after us.
我们必须离开这儿
We need to get out of here.
往北走 去加拿大
Go north, cross to Canada.
这活儿谁都能干
Anyone can do that job.
我可以给你5万美元
I'll give you $50,000.
你是怎么找到我的
How did you find me, huh?
你带给我的麻烦已经够多的了
'Cause you are fucking up my life, lady!
追你们的那帮人现在盯上我了
The people after you, they're on my ass now!
你被人认出来了
Sightings were posted.
- 劳拉 到里面去  - 被谁认出来了
- Laura, go inside.  - What sightings?
有人说看到一个长得很像金刚狼的人
People said someone who looked like the Wolverine
在厄尔巴索当司机
was in El Paso, driving.
还说他看上去老了
Said he looked old.
嘿
Hey!
我警告过你别再玩那个球了
I told you to stop it with that ball!
- 你这个臭丫头  - 不 求你了
- Bad girl!  - No, please.
- 我警告过你 臭丫头  - 不 求你了
- I told you, bad girl!  - No, please.
你可得赔钱给我
Mamacita's gonna have to pay for that.
求你了 别说了
Stop, please. No.
见鬼
Shit!
他们得赔偿我的损失
They're gonna have to pay for damages.
她身上有钱
And she has cash.
我看到的
I've seen it.
带着你的肥臀滚回你的办公室
You should get your fat ass back in your office.
她会赔你钱的
You'll get your money.
别让她打给任何人了 求你了
Don't let her call anyone, please.
他们会找到我们的 然后杀了我们
They will find us. They will kill us.
我是名护士
I am a nurse.
曾经是 在墨西哥城
Was. In Mexico City.
什么时候受伤的
When did that happen?
今天早上 在边界处
This morning. Near the border.
我逃了出来 不过
I got away from them, but...
由于缺少新生变种人 研究人员备受困扰
水中是否被添加了某种物质
基因改造
儿科癌症研究
现在他们认得我的车了
now they know my car.
听着 我得走了
Look, I gotta go.
不 等等 求你了
No, wait. Please. Here.
等等 快看
Please, wait! Look.
给你 你拿着 这里是2万美元
Look. Here, take this. It's $20,000.
拿着 带我们去上面的地址
Here. Take us to this address.
等你到了那儿我再给你3万
You can have $30,000 more when we get there.
我朋友到时候会给你
My friends there will give it to you.
他们在等我们
They will be waiting.
你要什么他们都会给你的
They will give you anything.
这些钱哪儿来的
Where did you get this?
我男朋友的
My boyfriend.
他想要杀了我 然后带走她
He wants to kill me and take her.
那是你女儿
And that's your daughter?
是的
Yes.
我知道你是个好人
I know you're still good inside.
我知道你会帮我们的
I know you want to help us.
你根本不了解我
You don't know anything about me.
求你了
Please!
我保证 如果现在就走的话 不会有事的
I promise, there will be no problems if we leave now.
我不能就这么离开去北达科他州
I can't just leave to North Dakota!
- 我们必须周五前赶到那儿  - 否则怎样
- We have to be there Friday.  - Or what?
否则我们就没法过境
Or we miss our chance to cross.
求你了
Please.
帮帮我们 求你了
You have to. Please.
求你了
Please.
我喜欢你的老花镜
I like those.
这样看上去年轻点
They make you look younger.
- 请快点  - 在路上了
查尔斯 听着 我得走了
Charles, listen.
我可能要离开几天 好吗
I gotta go away for a few days, okay?
我得跑趟长途挣笔大钱
I got a long ride for some good money...
回来后我们就离开这里
but when I get back, we're gonna get outta here.
我们开车去叶莱巴
We're gonna drive down to Yelapa.
然后再买艘船
We're gonna get ourselves a boat.
从此就住在海上
And we're gonna go live on the ocean.
到那儿就会安全了
Will you be safe there?
是的 当然 我们会安全的
Yeah. We'll be safe.
看罗根给我们带了什么 查尔斯
Look what Logan got us, Charles.
过几天就回来
Be back in a few days.
见鬼
Shit.
他们来了 请你...
- 罗根  - 什么？
- Logan.  - Yeah?
发生什么事了
What happened?
出什么事了吗
Did something go wrong?
这活儿一开始就是个错误
The job was wrong to begin with.
罗根
Logan!
干嘛
What?
这些东西是谁的
Who does this belong to?
那是谁
Who's that?
你为什么没能预见这破事
Thought you were supposed to see shit coming.
我可以追踪变种人
I can track mutants.
我能嗅出很多东西 可我不是千里眼
I'm a glorified truffle pig, not a clairvoyant.
到里面去 别让查尔斯出声
Go inside and keep Charles quiet.
到里面去 快
Go inside now!
调头出去 混蛋
You need to turn around, asshole.
这是私人领地
This is private property.
是的 没错
Yes, it is.
事实上我记得这里应该属于
In fact, I believe it belongs
一家总部在上海的
to a multinational smelting company...
跨国冶炼公司
based in Shanghai.
你把老家伙藏哪儿了
Where are you keeping the old man? Hmm?
他在里面吗
Is he over there?
还是在这里
Or is he there?
点子不错
That'd be smart.
我想见见他
I'd like to meet him.
我听说国土安全局已经把他的大脑
I'm told the HSA classifies his brain
列为大规模杀伤性武器了
as a weapon of mass destruction now.
在东部发生的事真是可惜了
Damn shame, what happened back east.
他已经死了一年了
He's been dead for a year.
我需要那女孩儿
I need the girl.
什么女孩儿
What girl?
你手里那只球的主人
The one that goes along with that ball you're holding.
这里没有女孩儿
There's no girl here.
我知道你去过那家汽车旅馆
I know you went to the motel.
是的 有人订了车
Yeah, I was called there.
没有女孩儿 只有一个女人
There was no girl. It was just the woman.
只有一个女人 说得没错
Just the woman. Such as she was.
那么 你见过加芙列拉了
So, you saw Gabriela.
可你没有打给我 真是伤心
But you didn't call me. That hurts.
该不会是你朝她开的枪吧
You didn't shoot the poor thing, did you?
- 不 你呢  - 是我先问你的
- No, did you?  - I asked you first.
- 我不喜欢用枪  - 当然了
- I don't like guns.  - Of course.
真希望你有打给我 罗根
I wish you'd called me, Logan.
按照我说的那样
Like I asked.
看见没
See?
不是只有你一个人被改造过
You're not the only one that's been enhanced.
罗根 罗根
Logan. Logan!
这位是劳拉
This is Laura.
卡利班 快来
Caliban, come!
这位就是我一直和你提起的
This is who I've been telling you about.
这位是劳拉
This is Laura.
我们一直都在等你
We've been waiting for you.
我们一直都在等你（西班牙语）
过来 快过来
Come, come here.
没事了
It's okay.
过来
Come.
劳拉
Laura.
没事了 没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
过来
Come.
来吧 没事的 你可以留在这儿 劳拉
Come. It's okay. You can stay here, Laura.
这儿很安全
It's safe.
在这儿我们可以照顾你
We can look after you here.
来吧
Come on.
看着像退役军人 也可能是个赏金猎人
Looks like ex-military. Bounty hunter, maybe?
更糟
Worse.
就他一个人？
Is he by himself?
对 但只是暂时的
Yeah, not for long.
把他搬上车
You get him back in his ride,
扔到干河床那儿去
take him out to the wash and dump him.
如果他半路醒了怎么办
What if he wakes up before I get there?
发消息告诉我你在哪儿 我们去接你
Text me where you are. We'll pick you up.
对 没错
Yes.
罗根
Logan.
- 罗根  - 嘿 嘿
- Logan.  - Hey. Hey!
等我搞明白你和你妈妈的
You'll get it back after I figure out
来龙去脉 我会还给你的
what you and your mother have got us into.
- 不 罗根  - 干嘛
- No, Logan.  - What?
我觉得 你可能
I think the...
罗根 你遇到的那个女人并不是她的妈妈
Logan, the woman that you met, that's not her mother.
- 所以她会说话  - 我们一直都有交流
- So she talks?  - We're communicating.
交流 好吧
Communicating.
快把这些药吃了
Take these now.
我们得马上离开 这里已经不安全了
We have to get out of here. It's not safe here anymore.
你不能在外面发作 明白吗
And you can't have an attack out there, you understand?
好的 可她就是我告诉你的那个新变种人
Yes, but this is the mutant that I told you about.
- 她需要帮助  - 她不是变种人
- She needs our help.  - She's not a mutant.
- 不 她是变种人  - 那她的天赋是什么 查尔斯
- Yes, she is!  - What's her gift, Charles?
吃东西 还是扔钢管
Eating? Pipe throwing?
没事的
It's okay.
只是火车经过
小火车 只是火车经过而已
别担心 火车而已
好了
Oh, yeah.
拿着枪 把尸体扔了
Take the gun. Dump the body.
回来的时候发消息给我
Text me when you're on the way back.
还有什么需要的吗
You have anything else you need?
孩子吃的食物
Food for the kid?
这下你完蛋了 变种人
You're fucked now, mutie.
别担心
It's okay.
只是另一辆火车经过而已
这次不是火车了
It's not a choo-choo.
没事的 坐下吧
It's okay. Sit down.
- 我们得走了  - 什么
- We gotta go.  - What?
- 出什么事了  - 待在这儿 去哪儿
- What's going on? Where?  - Stay here.
- 别乱动  - 我们要去哪儿
- Don't move.  - Where are we going?
别担心 他会回来找你的
Hey, don't worry. He will be back for you.
罗根 那女孩儿 你得回去接那女孩儿
Logan, the girl. You've got to go back for the girl.
罗根 那女孩儿怎么办
Logan, what about the girl?
罗根
Logan.
罗根 我们不能丢下劳拉
Logan, we mustn't forget about Laura.
她不归我们管
She's not our problem.
见鬼
Shit!
Ah, shit!
（西班牙语）
罗根
Logan.
嗯 我在想办法
Yeah, I'm thinking.
那个孩子
The child.
罗根 我们不能丢下劳拉
Logan, we mustn't forget Laura.
- 求你别说了  - 罗根
- Please be quiet.  - Logan.
- 查尔斯·泽维尔  - 卡利班在哪儿
- Charles Xavier.  - Where's Caliban?
美国头号八旬通缉犯
America's most wanted octogenarian.
准确说我已经九十多岁了
I'm a nonagenarian, actually.
卡利班在哪儿
Where's Caliban?
不如你先告诉我那女孩儿在哪儿
Why don't you tell me where the girl is first?
或者我可以问老光头 他看起来比较友善
Or I could ask Cue Ball. He seems quite friendly.
我说了 她不在我这里
I told you, she's not here.
卡利班在哪儿 你这个混蛋
Where's Caliban, motherfucker?
我把他扔到了原本你为我
Well, I left him in the same ditch
预留的沟里
he was gonna leave me in.
天啊 金刚狼
Jesus, Wolverine,
看到你这副样子我真是太心碎了
seeing you like this just breaks my damn heart.
真不想亲手把你的心挖出来碾碎
As soon as I rip it out of your chest, fuck-stick.
把她带来
Go get her.
劳拉
Laura.
就是她
That a girl!
嘿 宝贝
Hey, baby.
劳拉
Laura...
Laura!
宝贝 待在原地别动
Honey, you wanna stay where you are.
你想见你的朋友是吗
You wanna see your friends, right?
打死那个变种人
指挥官 别这样
Command, stop.
你不是说无论生死吗
You said alive or dead.
劳拉
Laura!
Laura.
劳拉
不 不
No. No.
动手 快
Move! Go!
开枪 快
停止射击
Stop shooting!
她能自愈 快追 好了 去追
She heals! Move! Go!
天啊
Holy shit!
抓住你了
Gotcha!
快点 抓住她
Come on, hold her down.
我早就告诉你了 罗根 她和你一样是变种人
As I told you, Logan, she's a mutant like you.
坐稳了
Hold on!
和你非常像
Very much like you.
劳拉 你没事吧
Laura, are you all right?
快追
Move!
坐稳了
Hold on!
该死 快啊
Fuck! Come on!
快啊
Come on!
见鬼
Shit.
列阵 给我追
Fall in! Let's go!
小心
Oh, watch out!
坐回去
Sit back.
把追踪者带来
Bring me the tracker.
你
You.
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
嘿 我在问你话呢 你是谁
Hey! I asked you a question. Who are you?
你知道他是谁 罗根
You know who she is, Logan.
不 我不知道
No, I don't.
你不觉得她很像谁吗
Does she remind you of anybody?
我小的时候读到过你的故事
I read about you when I was a kid.
我想你认错人了
I believe you're thinking of someone else.
如果我没记错 你曾经也为我们效过力吧
Now, if I'm not mistaken, you used to work for my team.
你帮我们围捕过那些变种人
You were helping round up all those old mutes.
现在怎么变了
What changed?
你信教了？
You got religion?
我需要你帮我们
I'm gonna need you to do
这样的好人再做一件事
one more thing for the good guys...
再帮我追踪一个特别的变种人
and track one more special mute for me.
我不会帮你的
I'm not helping you.
你知道你会这么说
Of course, you'd say that.
不过我总觉得人的本质是不会变的
But I got a theory that people don't really change.
小心光
Beware of the light.
卡利班 我猜小时候 你妈妈肯定每天
Caliban, I bet that's what your mama told you
都这么和你说吧
every day when you was a kid.
小心光
Beware of the light.
好了 别让我们互相撕破脸皮
Now, let's not bring out the worst in each other.
为了那女孩儿不值得
The girl is not worth it, trust me.
你们不一样 她生下来不是变种人
She's not a natural fuck-up like you.
他是公司犯下的错误 研发失误
She's a business mistake, a R&D gone bad.
就是个累赘
There's liability.
不能就这么让专利产品
They can't have things with patents
到处乱跑 伤害无辜不是吗
running around, hurting people, can they?
在她伤害别人之前
We need to get her off the board
我们得把她带回去
before she hurts anybody else.
或许下一个就是你在乎的人
Someone you care about, maybe.
好好闻一闻吧
So, get to sniffin'.
我叫做加芙列拉·洛佩兹
My name is Gabriela López.
我是名护士
I am a nurse.
过去十年我一直在为
And for 10 years, I worked for
墨西哥城的基因改造研究所工作
Transigen Research in Mexico City.
该研究所属于一家美国公司
Transigen is owned by an American company.
接下来你们看到的 在美国和加拿大
What I am about to show you is illegal...
都是非法的
in the U.S. And Canada.
阿尔卡利实验室 实验备忘录
桑德尔·莱斯博士 癌症项目主管
他说我们是研究药物的
They told us we were part of a pharmaceutical study.
当然 这都是骗人的
But, of course, that was a lie.
这些孩子都出生在研究所里
These children were born in Transigen.
他们出生在这里
They were born here...
然后就再也没离开过
and have never left.
他们从来没见过阳光和大海
They have never seen the sun or the ocean...
雨水或飘雪
rain or snow...
或者上帝的其他造物
or any of God's creatures.
他们没有出生证明
They have no birth certificates...
没有名字
no names...
除了我们给他们的代号
besides the ones we have given them.
他们都是在墨西哥女孩的肚子里孕育出来的
They were raised in the bellies of Mexican girls.
孩子出生后女孩儿就再也找不到了
Girls no one can find anymore.
他们的父亲都是些
Their fathers are semillas genéticas...
基因种子
special seeds in bottles.
- 有过生日吗  - 玛利亚
- Birthday? No birth. - María.
万圣节别给孩子打扮
We do not dress them up for Halloween.
别叫他们宝贝 也别叫他们亲亲
We do not call them "baby" or kiss boo-boos.
别把他们看作孩子
Don't think of them as children.
当他们是产品
Think of them as things...
有专利有版权的产品
with patents and copyrights.
明白吗
Comprende?
明白
Si, señor.
他们以为我们又穷
They thought we were too poor
又傻根本不理解
and stupid to understand.
我们是很穷
We're poor, yes...
可我们并不傻
but we are not stupid.
运用你的能力
Use your powers.
这是桩生意
This is business.
他们在制造士兵
They are making soldiers.
杀人机器
Killers.
这些年幼的变种人
These are babies of mutantes...
北达科他州
North Dakota.
你拿了那女人的钱
You took that woman's money.
你答应会带那孩子去那儿的
You said you would take the child there.
他是什么人
What is she?
她是你女儿 罗根
She's your daughter, Logan.
阿尔卡利有你的遗传密码
Alkali has your genetic code.
不只是我的
Not just mine.
罗根
Logan...
我不想谈这事儿
I don't want to talk about it.
也不想听你再说下去
I don't wanna hear about it anymore.
- 罗根  - 别再说了
- Logan...  - Just stop.
我想尿尿
I have to pee.
最后一次
Last ride.
不客气
You're welcome.
住手 看在上帝的份上
Stop it. For God's sake,
我自己能行
I can do this myself!
对 可你并没有成功
Yeah, well, you're not doing it.
赶紧尿吧
Just get on with it.
你站在那我怎么尿
Not with you standing there.
放心 我不会偷看的
Trust me, I'm not lookin'.
小姑娘
Hello.
你好
Hi, there!
知道吃东西要给钱吧
You know you gotta pay for that, right?
你爸爸妈妈在哪里
Hey! Where's your mommy and daddy, huh?
过来
Come on.
闹够了 这个给我
That's enough. These, too.
- 我靠  - 不能这样
- Shit!  - Not okay!
抱歉
Sorry.
手机充电器有吗
Um, do you sell phone chargers?
快走 到车上去
Come on. Get in the car.
随着孩子慢慢长大
As the children became older...
劳拉 劳拉
Laura. Laura.
他们变得越来越难相处
They became more difficult.
我们控制不了他们
They could not be controlled.
公司把他们变成了武器
The company made their bodies into weapons.
开始教他们如何杀人
Tried to teach them to kill.
可他们不想战斗
But they did not want to fight.
不想打仗的士兵对他们来说毫无意义
A soldier who will not fight is useless.
在这栋大楼里
Inside this building...
他们还在研究新的东西
they are working on something new.
一个比这些孩子更强的东西
Something they think is better than the children.
身份代码：X-24
他们说那是个没有灵魂的东西
Something they say is without a soul.
莱斯博士 你看过完整的报告了吗
Would you like to hear my full lab report, Dr. Rice?
这里吃不到寿司
You can't get good sushi here.
这里就像科罗拉多州的丹佛
It's the Mexican equivalent of Denver, Colorado.
他们肯定已经成功了
They must have been successful.
大约一周以前 他们告诉我们要停止项目
About a week ago, they told us to shut our program down.
他们开始对那些孩子实施安乐死
They started putting the children to sleep.
我们要救出尽可能多的孩子
We are going to save as many children as we can.
我知道一个地方 在北方
I read about a place, up north.
一个属于变种人的地方
A place for mutants.
他们称之为伊甸园
They call it Eden.
如果你看到了这段视频
If you are watching this...
那证明我已经死了
it means that I am dead.
我不知道还有没有其他幸存下来的孩子
I am not sure if any other children survived.
我们走散了
We were separated.
没有另一笔钱
There is no more money.
是我骗了你
That was a lie.
她不是我的孩子
She's not my child.
可我爱她
But I love her.
你可能不会像我一样爱她
You may not love her.
可她是你的孩子
But she is your child.
求你了 我请求你
Please. I beg you...
把她送到安全的地方
take her to safety.
我们要躲在这里吗
Is this where we're hiding out?
我们不躲
We're not hiding out.
找个地方睡几个小时
We're gonna get a couple of hours' sleep...
清洗一下 找几件新衣服
clean up, get some new clothes,
换俩新车离开这里
get a new ride and get outta here.
哈拉大赌场
Harrah's Hotel and Casino
欢迎您来到俄克拉荷马市
welcomes you to Oklahoma City.
要使用停车服务请靠右行驶
Please keep right for valet parking.
嘿
Hey.
欢乐尽在哈拉大赌场
The fun never stops at Harrah's Hotel and Casino.
就停在门口 好吗
Hey, keep it out front, all right?
快点 我们走
Come on, let's go.
嘿 劳拉
Hey, Laura.
我们走
Let's go.
我们需要衣服
We need clothes.
电梯上行
Going up.
不 住手 这不是玩具
No, no, stop. Not a toy.
- 不 不 不 抱歉 有轮椅  - 好吧
- Uh, no, no, sorry, chair.  - What? Okay.
- 再往上 - 谢谢
- Push up again. - Thank you.
上行
Going up.
过来 站好 站好了
Come here. Stand there. Just stand there.
罗根 这个给你
Logan, it's yours.
什么
What?
现在不用
I'm not gonna wear it now.
等到了房间里我再换
In the room. We'll get changed in the room.
你这个卑鄙的美国佬
You're a low-down, lying Yankee.
拿出证据
Prove it.
原野奇侠 Shane (1953)
这是一部很有名的电影 劳拉
This is a very famous picture, Laura.
都快有一百年了
It's almost 100 years old.
无论天上人间
In life, in death, oh, Lord
求主与我同住
Abide with me
我第一次看这部电影
I first saw this picture
是在我家乡的埃索达电影院里
at the Essoldo Cinema in my hometown...
当时我和你差不多大
when I was your age.
愿人都尊你的名为圣 愿你的国降临
Who art in heaven Hallowed be thy name
愿你的旨意行在地上
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done
基因改造
儿科癌症研究
见鬼
Shit.
已植入艾德曼金属
基因源：詹姆斯·豪利特
《非凡X战警》
我听说你是个卑鄙的
I've heard that you're a low-down,
美国佬
Yankee liar.
拿出证据
Prove it.
你平时就看这个？
You read these in your spare time?
看啊 查尔斯 X战警有新粉丝了
Oh, yeah, Charles, we got ourselves an X-Men fan.
你知道里面都是瞎写的吧
You do know they're all bullshit, right?
可能其中四分之一确有其事 但也不是这样
Maybe a quarter of it happened, and not like this.
在现实世界里人会死
In the real world, people die.
也没有穿着紧身衣
And no self-promoting asshole
自命不凡的傻子来救他们
in a fucking leotard can stop it.
这就是用来安慰失败者的冰激凌
This is ice cream for bed-wetters.
罗根
Logan...
那女的一直都在给她灌输美丽的童话
Her nurse has been feeding her some grade-A bullshit.
我觉得劳拉不需要别人
I don't think Laura needs reminding
提醒她生命无常
of life's impermanence.
你不是说要找辆新车吗
Didn't you say something about finding us a new ride?
一个小时后吃两粒
Two more pills in one hour.
记得给他
Give 'em to him.
为什么 谢恩
Why, Shane?
人必须忠于自己 乔伊
A man has to be what he is, Joey.
不能违背自己的本性
Can't break the mold.
我试过了 可最终还是不行
I tried it and it didn't work for me.
乔伊 带着杀戮活下去很艰难
Joey, there's no living with a killing.
这条路没有退路
There's no going back from one.
是对是错 你都得背负
Right or wrong, it's a brand.
直至一生
A brand sticks.
现在快回去找你妈妈
Now you run on home to your mother,
告诉她一切都好
and tell her everything's all right.
山谷里再不会有枪声了
And there aren't any more guns in the valley.
你们是谁
Who are you guys?
又是警察？ 可我已经
More cops? 'Cause I told
把我知道的都告诉了
the other guys everything that I...
暂停营业
起来 到笼子里去 追踪者
Get up! In your cage, tracker.
已经没你的事了
You did your job.
伙计们
Fellas.
见鬼
Shit.
送你们了
Knock yourselves out.
最低8000
I'll tell you what. Eight grand...
我可以帮你喷新漆 换一下轮胎
I'll have her freshly painted for you, new tires...
安装调试好 再帮你把手续办了
mounted, balanced, and complete paperwork.
我给你10000
I'll give you 10 as-is,
手续的事就跳过吧
if you can forget the paperwork.
你还是需要换轮胎 不换不行
Well, you still need new tires, man, they're bald.
多久能办好
How long will that take?
一个小时
An hour.
伊甸园 还是终结？
搞什么鬼
Jesus.
北达科他州
这是在逗我吗
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
先生 你的钥匙
Sir, are the keys in... Sir!
你的钥匙在车里吗 先生
You have the keys in it? Sir!
该死
Shit!
查尔斯 查尔斯
Charles. Charles!
上行
Going up.
见鬼
Oh, shit!
你没事吧
You all right?
我们得赶紧离开
We gotta get outta here.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
真的很抱歉
紧急救护人员仍在
Emergency personnel are still on scene
俄克拉荷马市的哈利士赌场旅馆
at Harrah's Casino Hotel in Oklahoma City...
昨日至少400人出现
where at least 400 guests were stricken
暂时性麻痹症状
with temporary paralysis yesterday.
受伤情况大都和
Many are noting a similarity
一年前的韦斯切斯特事故十分相似
to the Westchester incident over a year ago...
当时有超过600人受伤
that left over 600 injured...
7名变种人身亡
and took the lives of seven mutants,
其中包括几名X战警
including several of the X-Men.
别玩了
Knock it off.
让你别玩了
I said, knock it off!
她只是个孩子 罗根
She's a child, Logan.
事实上 她是你的
And, point of fact, she's your...
上次吃药是什么时候
How long has it been since you took your meds?
告诉我 隔了多久
Tell me, how long has it been?
我不知道
I don't know!
两天吧
Two days.
昨天发生的事你也看到了
You saw what happened yesterday.
要不是我及时赶到
If that shit had gone on any longer,
赌场里那些人不就...
everyone in that casino...
我只是尽我所能保护劳拉
I did what I had to do to save Laura.
你什么都做不了
You didn't do anything.
你只是受了惊吓发病了而已
You just freaked out and had a fucking seizure!
我想你更喜欢我吃了药像疯子一样
I guess you prefer me pharmaceutically castrated,
语无伦次的模样吧
rambling on like a lunatic.
这样你就能轻松些
So much easier for you.
轻松个屁
Easier? Jesus!
和你在一起就不会轻松 从来不会
There is nothing easy about you, Charles, nothing!
就像这世上其他人一样
Yes, yes, please be like the rest of the world...
把自己的过错都怪罪到别人头上
blaming someone else for your boring shit.
我懂 老爹 你对我太失望了
I know, Pop, I'm such a giant disappointment.
你真的打心底不明白
You honestly derive no sense of purpose...
我们为什么要这么做吗
from what we're doing?
好吧 那我们到底在做什么
Okay, what are we doing? Hmm?
有一个新生的变种人坐在我们的车上
There is a young mutant sitting in our car.
对 没错
Yeah, I see that.
而我们要去的地方还有其他的孩子
And where we're taking her, there are others.
难道你还看不出这意味着什么吗
Does that mean nothing to you?
是的 我看不出个所以然
Yeah, means nothing to me.
尤其是当我知道那个护士
Especially since Nurse Gabriela...
说的伊甸园是根据漫画胡编乱造出来的之后
made all that Eden shit up with fucking comic books.
你在说些什么
What are you talking about?
你把这个给他
Give those to him, will you?
该吃药了 拿两片给他
Take out two pills and give them to him.
- 罗根 罗根  - 把药给她
- Logan! Logan!  - Give 'em to him.
快点
Now!
张嘴我看看
I wanna see it.
莱斯博士 我们马上就能...
Dr. Rice. It's under control...
该死的无人卡车
Motherfucking auto-trucks.
别爆粗口 罗根
Language, Logan.
你冲着一台机器发火干嘛
And you're screaming at a machine.
干嘛 她可以杀人不眨眼
Oh, what? She can gut a man with her feet,
却听不得脏话吗
she can't hear a few naughty words, huh?
我们可以教她成为更好的人
She can learn to be better.
你是说和我比吗
You mean, better than me?
一点儿没错
Actually, yes.
还有 劳拉脚上的爪子
And, by the way, Laura's foot claws...
很显然是由于性别所致
are the obvious result of her gender, you know.
是吗
Is that a fact?
在狮群当中 母狮子
In a pride of lions, the female...
既要负责捕猎 又要负责照顾狮群
is both hunter and caregiver.
真长知识
Good to know.
她们用前爪捕猎
She uses her front claws for hunting...
用后爪防御
and the back claws defensively.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
这样才能幸存下来
Thus, ensuring their survival.
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey!
我们得帮他们一把
We should help them.
不 我们得赶路 有人会来帮忙的
No, we have to keep going. Someone will come along.
不就是我们吗
Someone has come along.
警报 警报
Alert. Alert.
嘿 要帮忙吗
Hey, uh, you need a hand?
准备好 推
Ready? Go!
很好 搞定了
Ah. Good, got it.
好了 我们回家吧
Come on, let's get home.
劳拉
Laura!
谢谢你们的帮忙
Thank you so much for your help.
- 我叫凯瑟琳  - 詹姆斯
- I'm Kathryn.  - James.
我儿子内特
This is my son, Nate.
- 嗨  - 嘿
- Hi.  - Hey.
那是你女儿？
That's your daughter?
对 她叫劳拉 那是我父亲
Yeah, that's Laura, and that's my dad...
查克
Chuck.
好了 劳拉 该走了
Come on, Laura, let's go.
我想请你们到我们家
Well, can we show our appreciation
吃顿晚饭以示感谢
and treat the three of you to a decent meal?
我们家离这儿不远
We don't live far from here.
- 不用了  - 那真是太好了
- Uh, no, thanks.  - That would be lovely!
我是莱斯博士
My name is Dr. Rice.
如果你喜欢也可以叫我桑德尔
But you can call me Zander if you like.
我同事告诉我
My colleague tells me
你不太愿意配合我们
you've been somewhat resistant.
他说你给他的消息
He believes you've been
总是不及时
dispensing delayed information...
所以你的朋友总是快我们一步
to allow your friends to stay one step ahead.
我现在是在给你
I'm offering you the possibility
赎罪的机会 卡利班
of redemption, Caliban.
去保护这个世界 同时
To protect the world, and in the process,
拯救你的朋友
save your friends.
而那个小女孩儿只是一个小小的代价而已
The girl is a rather small price to pay for that.
她不是你的同类
Unlike you, she's impure.
她不是天生的变种人
She wasn't made by nature.
她只是我犯下的一个错误
She's a mistake of my own.
我尽了全力
I did what I could
可他们用光照我 打我
and they burned me and beat me.
你的同事都是群野蛮人
Your colleagues are savages.
我同意
I agree.
那些掠夺者都是群废物
The Reavers were very ineffective.
不过我带了新的帮手来
But I'm bringing new tools to bear.
可我还是需要有人
But I still need someone
为我们指明方向
to point us in the right direction.
不 我帮不了你
No, I can't help you.
别激动 别激动
Breathe, breathe.
那个老头现在情况有多糟糕？
Now, what does he have? The old man.
老年痴呆 渐冻症？
Alzheimer's? ALS?
世界上最危险的大脑
A degenerative brain disease
居然得了脑退化
in the world's most dangerous brain?
真是讽刺
What a combo.
开饭了 我们有客人 规矩点
Be nice. Now, you know we got company.
真是太好了
That's wonderful.
快请坐
Everybody, have a seat.
内特快坐好
Nate, sit up.
詹姆斯 你坐在桌子那边吧
James, why don't you sit at the end of the table?
你来做祷告好吗 来吧宝贝
You wanna say grace? Say grace, baby.
感谢上帝 赐予我们食物
Uh, thank you, God, for this food...
还有感谢我们的新朋友
and for our new friends, the Howletts.
感谢他们的帮忙
Mmm. They came to our aid.
- 阿门  - 阿门
- Amen.  - Amen.
阿门 给你查尔斯
Here we go. Here you go, Charles.
多谢
Thank you, sir.
如果她想吃还有很多
Oh, there's plenty more if she wants.
不用了 谢谢
She's fine. Thank you.
菜的味道很好
This is delicious.
- 谢谢  - 真的很好吃
- Oh, thank you.  - It's so good.
你们要去哪里？
Where are you all headed?
- 俄勒冈州  - 南达科他州
- Uh... Oregon.  - South Dakota.
先去俄勒冈 然后再去南达科他
Well, Oregon and then South Dakota.
去度假吗
Vacation?
没错
Uh... Yes.
计划了很久了
Uh, long overdue.
我们住在城市里
We're city folk.
一直都想沿着公路自驾游 看看整个国家
Always wanted to take a road trip, see the country.
还有看看不同的风土人情
Um... And meet the people in it.
听起来很棒
That sounds lovely.
我一直都想说服威尔
Been trying to get Will here
去度假 都好几年了
to take a vacation for years now.
如果我们到处旅游
Oh. If we go traipsing all over the country,
谁来打理这个地方
who's gonna take care of this place?
没错 所以才让你卖了农场
Exactly. I say, let it go.
那靠什么养家
And live off what?
上帝会眷顾我们的
The Lord will provide.
我还在等上帝赐予我一台
I'm still waiting for the Lord to provide me
新的打谷机呢
with a new thresher.
反正总有一天我会去旅行的
All the same, I'd love to travel someday.
我相信会有那么一天的
And I bet you will.
- 我可以退学  - 行了 别说得像真的一样
- I could drop out of school.  - Okay, let's not go that far.
我说真的
I mean, I'll do it.
- 不行  - 为什么不行
- No. No.  - Why not?
你不是想去旅行吗 我也想
You wanna travel, I wanna travel.
行了儿子
Son. Son.
正合你意对吧
That sounds good to you, right?
简直就是完美
This is the perfect plan.
为什么想要退学呢 内特
Why would you want to do that, Nate?
注意了 他可是个创办过学校的人
Careful, you're speaking to a man who ran a school...
还开了好多年对吧 查尔斯
for a lot of years. Right, Charles?
好吧 是的 那是一所
Yes, it was a...
一所为特殊孩子开设的学校
It was a special needs school. Um...
这个解释不错
Uh-huh. That's a good description.
他也在那儿
He was there, too.
对 没错
Oh, yeah, no. Um...
我还被开除过几次
I got kicked out a few times.
我也希望能夸你是个好学生
I wish I could say you were a good pupil,
可我就是说不出口
but the words would choke me.
真的非常感谢你们的款待
Ma'am, I can't thank you enough for this.
今晚真的很棒
Uh, it was great.
不过我们还得赶路
But we have a long drive ahead of us, so...
可你们总得休息吧
But you need to rest, don't you?
我们会找到旅馆的
Yeah, we'll find a motel somewhere.
最近的开过去也要两个小时
The nearest one is two hours from here
条件还不怎么样
and it's not even that nice.
我们楼上有个空房间
We have a perfectly fine room upstairs
可以给你父亲和女儿住
for your father and your daughter and
而你可以睡在客厅的折叠沙发上
you can sleep in the living room on the convertible.
凯瑟琳 真的很感谢
Kathryn, it's very, very nice of you,
不过我们还是不打扰了
but we really should go.
我们可以明天一早再走
We can leave early in the morning.
天一亮就走 你觉得呢
Break of dawn, as it were.
好吧 那我给你洗漱一下吧 老爸
Okay, why don't we wash up, Pop?
好的
Okay.
坐下
Sit.
宝贝 要来点甜品吗
Um, sweetie, you want some dessert?
两天的路程
Two days on the road,
就吃了一顿饭 还几乎没睡过觉
only one meal, and hardly any sleep.
她才11岁 而我90了
She's 11, I'm fucking 90.
可我们有101个理由继续赶路
Well, that's 101 reasons to keep moving.
我不是一盒牛油果 罗根
I'm not a box of avocados, Logan.
所以呢 过了今晚然后呢
And then what? We stay the night, then what?
然后我们带她去伊甸园找她的朋友
Then we take her to her friends in Eden.
然后 然后我们就去买逐日号
And then we buy the Sunseeker.
先吃药
Take the pills.
见鬼
Oh, shit!
- 怎么了  - 内特
- What's going on?  - Nate!
趁还有点水压快去把浴缸放满
Go fill up the tub before we lose pressure.
亲爱的 检查下水槽
Honey, check the sink.
他们又把水给断了
They shut it off again.
他们就是不肯罢休
They are just not going to let this thing go.
你最好现在就去处理一下
Well, you might as well handle it now.
等到明天早上吧 昨晚刚下过雨
It can wait till the morning. We just had rain last night.
可家里还有客人
We got three houseguests
还有一大堆碟子没洗
and a sink full of dishes.
好吧 好吧
All right, all right.
供水站离这里
The pump station that supplies us
大概一英里半
is a mile and a half from here.
有的时候它会停止运作
Sometimes it gets itself shut off.
- 是那群混蛋  - 嘿
- By assholes.  - Hey!
别乱动
No.
我儿子可以和你一起去
My son is happy to go with you.
不 不 不 没关系
No, no, no, that's fine.
那些人有的时候不太...
The men that do this, sometimes they can be...
- 我和你一起去  - 不 你得做作业
- I can go.  - No, you got homework.
我和你去
All right, I'll go.
让我先安顿好我爸爸
Just, uh, let me get my dad settled.
来吧
All right.
我是说我不在乎律师说了什么
I'm just saying, I don't care what the lawyer says.
可这样很危险
But it's dangerous.
我不会让他们伤害我们的
I'm not gonna hurt our chances.
有电视 要看吗
Want TV? There's TV here.
不用了
I'm fine.
好吧 好好休息
Okay. Get some rest.
知道吗 罗根
You know, Logan...
生活就应该像这样
this is what life looks like.
一个家 家人彼此相爱
A home, people who love each other.
安全的港湾
Safe place.
你应该花时间感受一下
You should take a moment and feel it.
对 这儿很好
Yeah. It's great.
罗根 罗根
Logan. Logan!
你还有时间
You still have time.
查尔斯 世界已经变了样了
Charles, the world is not the same as it was.
待在这里我们会有风险 你知道的
We're taking a risk hanging around here, you know that.
还有我们要去的那个伊甸园
And where we're going, Eden...
其实并不存在
it doesn't exist.
它是护士从漫画书上看来的
Her nurse got it from a comic book.
你懂了吗 都是假的
You understand? It's not real.
对劳拉来说是真的
It is for Laura.
好好休息
Get some rest.
坎伍德饮料公司买下了这里的一切
Canewood Beverage bought up everything out here,
除了我们的农场
except for us.
我们不想卖 他们就想强行征用
When we wouldn't sell, they tried eminent domain...
然后断我们的水源
then screwing with our water.
几个月前有人下毒杀死了我们的狗
Couple of months ago, somebody poisoned our dogs.
所以今天在公路上也不是意外？
So, out on the highway today, those trucks...
我不知道 或许吧
Who knows. Maybe.
看看他们
Hey, look at 'em.
就像一只四肢发达
Look like dinosaurs with their 20-ton bodies
头脑简单的恐龙
and tiny little brains...
在给他们的超级转基因玉米剥壳
shucking their cloned-up super corn.
那玩意儿味道简直像屎一样
You know it tastes like shit, too.
那为什么还有人吃
Why do people eat it?
不是吃的 是用来喝的 玉米糖浆
They don't. They drink it. Corn syrup.
加了那东西 他们就能保持清醒
It's in those drinks that everyone's having...
很有精神 还能带来性欲什么的
to stay awake, cheer up, feel strong, sexy, whatever.
今时不同往日了 它能让你一杯解千愁
Used to be a time when a bad day was just a bad day.
可惜对我没用
Mine still are.
这些是套牛比赛赢来的
Those are for breakaway roping.
那些事绕桶比赛得来的
Those are for barrel racing...
还有这些 绕杆比赛得来的
and right here is for pole bending.
不过全是二三等奖
They're all second, third place.
我不是很在行 不过我爸爸硬要我参加
I'm not too good at it, but my dad makes me.
你想听吗
Do you want to listen?
喜欢吗
Do you like it?
给 借你听一晚
Um, here, you can take it for tonight...
明早你再还给我
and I'll get it back from you in the morning.
看来得弄一会儿了
Looks like we're gonna be here a while.
能撑一阵子
Should hold it.
没错
Yeah.
撑到下一次
Till next time.
谢谢
Thanks.
那么 你女儿那样
Hey, so, uh, how long has your girl
- 有多久了  - 什么
- been like that?  - Huh?
不说话
Mute.
从一开始就这样
Uh, since the beginning.
其实我还挺羡慕你的
Well, in a lot of ways, I envy you.
等她到了内特的年纪
They get to be Nate's age,
就不会说些蠢话了
with the nonsense that comes out of their mouths...
让你怀疑做父母的意义何在
Makes you wonder the whole point of it all.
见鬼
Shit.
别担心
Don't worry.
不会用上枪的
We won't need it.
待在这儿
Stay here.
晚上好 芒森先生
Evening, Mr. Munson.
什么风把你吹来了
What brings y'all this way?
你为什么不问问你的手下
Why don't you ask your boys?
芒森先生
Mr. Munson,
你知道你这样是非法入侵吧
you understand you're trespassing right now, right?
我和这里以前的主人
I have an easement with the previous owner
签订过地役权
of your property.
胡扯
Huh. Bullshit.
你也说是“前”主人了
"Previous" being the operative word.
他是谁？
Who's this?
劝你赶紧回
Just a guy telling you
车上去的好心人
to get back in your nice truck.
到别的地方去扮你的地痞流氓
Go play Okie dickhead somewhere else.
嘿 卡尔
Hey, Carl...
看来芒森先生雇了一个打手
it looks like Mr. Munson hired some muscle.
看起来是的
Looks that way.
他只是我的朋友
He's a friend of mine.
你朋友口气挺大
A friend with a big mouth.
这话我听得多了
I hear that a lot.
那你肯定也听过这个吧
Then you probably hear this, too.
多了去了
More than I'd like.
那你知道该怎么做了
Then you know the drill.
我数三下
I'mma count to three...
你们给我离开这儿
and you're gonna start walking away.
这里的水我有权使用
I got rights to this water.
- 一  - 我请了律师
- One.  - I have a lawyer now.
二
Two.
三
Three.
头儿 你还好吗
You all right, boss?
知道该怎么做了吧
You know the drill.
把帽子给我捡起来
Pick up my goddamn hat.
赶紧给我滚
Get the hell out of here.
- 头儿？  - 去你的
- You okay, boss?  - Fuck off.
滚
Go!
你受过训练
You've had training.
算是吧
Some.
先别叫醒她
Hey, don't wake her yet.
让她再睡一小时
Let her sleep another hour.
知道吗 罗根
You know, Logan...
毫无疑问 今天晚上
this was, without a doubt...
是我这么久以来度过的最美好的夜晚
the most perfect night I've had in a very long time.
可我并不配拥有它
But I don't deserve it.
不是吗
Do I?
我做过一些事
I did something.
一些不可言说的事
Something unspeakable.
发生在维斯切斯特的事我全记起来了
I've remembered what happened in Westchester.
这已经不是我第一次伤害别人了
This is not the first time I've hurt people.
只是在今天之前 我一直都不知道
Until today, I didn't know.
你也不告诉我
You wouldn't tell me.
所以我们就这样一直逃避下去
So we just kept on running away from it.
我想我终于能理解你了
I think I finally understand you.
罗根
Logan...
他简直完美
He's fantastic.
你说过你只要那个女孩儿
You said you only needed the girl!
我也说过我带了新帮手来
I told you I was forced to bring a new tool to bear.
我给过你朋友机会
Your friends had every chance.
你也是
And so did you.
内特
Nate?
放下她
Put her down.
亲爱的
Honey.
别上来 威尔
Stay down there, Will!
住手
Stop!
凯瑟琳
Kathryn!
查尔斯
Charles!
按住伤口
Hold this.
那不是我 那不是我
It wasn't me. It wasn't me.
他来了
Here he comes.
我可以过去
I could pick him up,
接他
meet him halfway.
不 让他们过来
No, no, no. Let them come to us.
X-23很不好对付
We struggled with the X-23s.
我们本以为能把这些孩子
We assumed, because they were children...
从小培养成冷血杀手
we could raise them without a conscience.
可愤怒是无法后天培养的
But you can't nurture rage.
你必须从一开始就为他
You must simply design it...
设定好
from scratch.
那又是该死的谁
Who the fuck is that?
威尔·芒森
Will Munson!
坚持住 查尔斯
Just hold on, Charles.
芒森 该死的 给我出来
Munson, God damn it, come out here!
芒森
Munson!
快给我出来
Come out here now!
给我滚出来 芒森
Come out here now, Munson.
是刚才那个混蛋
There's that asshole.
你好 混蛋
Hello, asshole.
听着 过去的事我就不计较了
Listen, I'm willing to let bygones be bygones.
我不知道芒森那家伙付你多少钱
I don't know what Munson's paying you...
我们坎伍德现在给你5000美元
but Canewood can start you out at five G.
我指一星期
A week, that is.
你最好待着别动 兄弟
You best stay where you are, pal.
我就是这里的法律
I'm the law out here.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
天杀的
What in high...
我靠
What? Oh, shit!
快开枪
Shoot him!
我们得介入了
We need to intervene.
可他只听你的话 博士
Well, he only listens to you, Doctor.
24!
快回来
Get back here!
住手 赶紧住手
Stop! Stop now!
快按住伤口 按紧
Hold this down, right now, tight!
- 我们的船  - 什么
- Our boat.  - What?
逐日号
The Sunseeker.
不
No.
回来
Come!
24!
快过来帮我
Need some help out here!
看来我们得出手了
I guess we're gonna have to take care of this now.
- 皮尔斯  - 把那个给我
- Pierce!  - Give me that.
你到底在磨蹭什么
Get your lily-faced ass out here!
听到没
Listen to me!
你到底在干什么
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
我们绕过那辆卡车
All right, we gotta go around that truck
从侧面袭击
and flank them farmers.
听我指挥
Follow my lead.
多带点子弹 把这些弹夹都带上
Bring extra ammo, take these clips.
给我
Come!
回来
Now!
把她带上
Pick her up.
小心光
Beware the light.
你到底是什么
What the hell are you?
坐下
Sit down.
别乱动
Hold still.
把他抬到卡车上去
Get him on the truck.
好
Yeah.
走吧
Go.
没事了 没事了
It's all right, it's all right.
你做得很好 24
It's all right. You did fine, 24.
你正在愈合 保持呼吸
You're healing. Just breathe.
严格来说 你还只是个新生儿
You're a newborn, by any measure.
保持呼吸
Just breathe.
你的身体还有许多工作要完成
Your body has work to do.
它需要止血 生成血管 还有表皮
Hemostasis, angiogenesis, epithelialization...
增生基质细胞
stromal cell proliferation.
这能帮助你恢复
This will help you heal.
让你变得更强
Make you stronger.
好吧
Well...
这里也算得上是傍水了
It's got water, and...
至少有水
It's got water.
该死的 该死的
Fuck this. Fuck this.
见鬼
God!
该死 该死
Fuck! Fuck!
该死
Fuck!
见鬼
Shit!
去死 去死
Fuck! Fuck!
去死
Fuck!
去你的
Motherfucking...
见鬼
Shit!
去死
Fuck! Fuck!
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
我刚才还在想 是不是该告诉
I was starting to think I was gonna have to tell...
休息室那小女孩儿
that nice little girl out in the waiting room...
她爸爸醒不过来了
her daddy's gone.
我一直希望
I'd always hoped...
能有机会遇到像你这样的人
that I'd get the chance to meet someone like you.
你的同类已经不多了
There's so few of you left.
我也很高兴认识你 医生
Nice to meet you, too, Doc.
可我必须得赶路了
But I really got to get on my way.
不 不 不 别这样
No, no, don't do that.
你需要休息 还有治疗
What you need is rest, and treatment.
你需要找个地方检查一下
You need to check yourself in somewhere.
- 我没事  - 不 你有事
- I'll be fine.  - No, you're not!
我是说 我知道你与众不同
I mean, I know that you're different...
不过这也无法改变
but that doesn't change the fact
你体内有东西在荼毒你的事实
that something inside you is poisoning you.
你得找家医院检查一下
You got to check yourself into a hospital.
看看到底怎么回事
Find out what it is!
我知道怎么回事
I know what it is.
求你了先生 如果你不想去医院的话
Please, mister, if you don't want to go to a hospital,
或许我可以帮你
maybe I can help you.
我可以帮你做测试
Maybe I can run some tests.
听着 医生 你看起来是个好人
Look, Doc. You seem like a nice guy, all right?
如果你想要救人的话 救你自己吧
You wanna save a life, save your own.
忘了我们来过这儿
Forget we were here.
我们走
Let's go.
你不能随便拿别人的
You can't just take shit, you know.
我不知道你怎么带我来这儿的
I don't know how you got me here...
不过谢谢
but thank you.
不客气
De nada.
好的
Yeah.
你会说话
You can talk?
见鬼
What the fuck?
那为什么
Why in the fuck...
我们开了2000英里
What's all this bullshit been
你一个字都不说
for the last 2,000 fucking miles?
什么 好吧
What? Shut up.
行了 闭嘴 给我闭嘴
Shut the fuck up!
约拿 吉迪恩 丽贝卡 黛利拉 瑞克特
Jonah, Gideon, Rebecca, Delilah, Rictor.
什么 他们是谁
What? Who's that?
他们是谁
Who is that?
约拿 吉迪恩 丽贝卡 黛利拉 瑞克特
Jonah, Gideon, Rebecca, Delilah, and Rictor.
北达科他州
North Dakota.
什么
What?
带我去北达科他州
North Dakota, por favor.
见鬼让我看
Shit, okay. Look...
不行
No. Por favor.
这个地方 对吧
This place. Okay?
你的护士
Your nurse,
漫画书看多了 明白吗
she read too many stories, you understand?
漫画书看太多了
Too many stories!
我看了 我看过了 懂吗
I've seen it! I've seen it, okay?
这上面画的
This all here...
所有的一切都不存在
None of this... No existo, okay?
明白了吗
You understand me?
- 上面的伊甸园 根本不存在  - 有伊甸园
- This Eden does not exist. No!  - Sí! Eden!
那是虚构的 孩子看到没
It's a fantasy, kid. See that?
上面写着画这些漫画的
Those are the names of the people
人的名字
who just made this...
这些都是他们编出来的
They made this whole thing up.
懂吗 这整个
Okay? This whole...
整个故事
It happened once,
一小部分是真的 其他的都是他们编出来的
and they just turned it into a big, fucking lie!
仅此而已 不
That's all this is. No!
见鬼
Fuck.
不
No.
我知道 我理解
I know, I understand.
这条路非常远
This is a long way.
明白吗
You understand?
我不会送你去北达科他州
I am not taking you to North Dakota.
我撑不下去了 我没法送你去那儿
I am fucked up. And I cannot get you there.
还要两天的路程 我不会送你去的
It is a two-day drive. And I am not taking you...
够了 别打了
Don't fucking hit me!
别再打了
Don't hit me!
约拿 吉迪恩
Jonah, Gideon...
- 别再念这些名字  - 丽贝卡
- Stop saying those names.  - Rebecca...
黛利拉 瑞克特
Delilah, Rictor.
听到没 别再念了
Right now. Stop saying those names.
- 停下  - 约拿 吉迪恩 丽贝卡
- Stop it! Stop! - Jonah, Gideon, Rebecca...
好吧 好吧
Fuck it. Fine, fine.
你想要去是吧
You wanna go?
我就带你去
I'll take you there.
你自己亲眼去看
See for yourself.
一起去你那该死的童话世界
Let's go to fucking fantasyland.
我们知道控制局面
We understand the importance
的重要性 莱斯博士
of containment, Dr. Rice.
可是不能像你之前在华瑞兹那样
But you can't leave a war zone behind
大动干戈啊
like you did in Juárez.
你可别忘了
Well, try to remind yourselves
这些都是杀人机器
that these are all little killing machines.
轻易就能杀掉你全家
Machines who would've happily disemboweled your family.
不都是啊
Not all.
我跟你说了把他们解决掉
I was told you want these assets off-board,
不管死活
dead or alive.
你改了我的命令吗
Are you changing my brief?
没有
No.
那还废什么话
All right, then.
提取他的细胞组织
Save tissue from this one.
他擅长追踪 具有高智商
He's a good tracker and had a high IQ.
拿去吧
Here you go.
让我开
Let me drive.
那可不行
Absolutely not.
别盯着我看
Quit looking at me.
听不懂
No comprende.
你快死了
You are dying.
你想死
You want to die.
查尔斯告诉我的
Charles told me.
他还告诉了你什么
What else did he tell you?
别让你死
To not let you.
休息吧
Rest.
稳住
Keep it steady.
往我这边来点
Swing him toward me.
好
Yeah.
慢点
Easy. Easy
这样可以吗 瑞克多
Is this good, Rictor?
不用那么多 少点儿
No, not so much. Less.
我在哪儿
Where am I?
这是什么
Hey, what is it?
从哪儿弄来的
Where did you get that?
从我们来的地方
Where we came from.
战斗时
They gave it to us
他们给我们这个 让我们变得更强
when we would fight. It makes you stronger.
那东西只会让你发狂
It makes you crazy, is what it does.
还会杀了你
It'll kill you.
不 如果你控制好剂量的话
No, not if you use it in small doses.
它会帮你恢复
It's helping you heal.
劳拉在哪儿
Where's Laura?
她在下面睡着了
She's asleep down there.
要我叫醒她吗
Do you want me to wake her up?
不
No.
你做噩梦了
You had a nightmare.
你会做噩梦吗
Do you have nightmares?
会
Sí.
梦里有人会伤害我
People hurt me.
我的不一样
Mine are different.
梦里我伤害了别人
I hurt people.
这个是什么
你知道这是什么吗
You know what it is.
这是用艾德曼合金做的
It's made out of Adamantium.
就是他们注入我们体内的东西
It's what they put inside of us.
所以它能杀死我们
That's why it can kill us.
或许正是它在要我的命
Probably what is killing me now.
反正
Anyway...
这是我很久以前得到的
I got this a long time ago...
我留着它是想提醒我 自己究竟是谁
and I kept it as a reminder of what I am.
现在我留着...
Now I keep it to, uh...
实话说
Actually, uh...
我想过用它来自杀
I was thinking of shooting myself with it.
查尔斯说得没错
Like Charles said.
我也伤害过人
I've hurt people, too.
你得学会如何面对这种感觉
You're gonna have to learn how to live with that.
他们都是坏人
They were bad people.
并没有差别
All the same.
不好玩 这一点都不好玩
Not funny. That is not funny!
嘿 小子
Hey! Hey, pal.
我睡了多久了
How long have I been out?
我在床上躺了多久了
How long have I been in that bed?
两天
Two days.
你们就在这儿守了两天？
You've been sitting here for two days?
进去告诉大家可以开始打包了
Hey, go inside and tell everyone to get packing.
你们不能这样 不能坐以待毙
You can't do that. You can't just stay here.
我们必须等待 计划就是这样的
We had to wait. It was the plan.
今天是我们集合的最后一天
And everyone had till today to find their way here.
再等下去
If you keep waiting,
阿尔卡利会找到你们 然后把你们全部杀掉
Alkali will find you and they will kill you all.
你们得离开这儿
You need to get out!
明天天亮前我们就走
We're leaving tomorrow before dawn.
我们会穿过边界去加拿大
We're gonna cross the border.
那里有避难所
It's a safe haven.
请确认坐标
Same coordinates?
已确认 正午到五点之间
Yes, between noon and 5:00.
那会儿卫星也看不到
Satellites are blind then.
- 你们的庇护要求已批准  - 收到
- Your asylum approved.  - Copy.
你往右边看 劳拉
Swing it to your right, Laura.
再往右一点 对
A little more. Yeah.
看到树林了吗
You see the woods?
嗯
Sí.
要走8英里才能到那儿
It's an eight mile hike through there.
看到那条通道没
And you see that pass?
那就是边界
That's the border.
到那里我们就安全了
That's where we will be safe.
进来吧
Come inside.
劳拉告诉我你为她所做的一切
Laura told me all that you did for her.
她很幸运有你在她身边
She was lucky to have you.
拿着吧 她说这是你的
Take it. She says it's yours.
这也是你送她来的目的吧
That's why you did it, right?
对 好吧
Yeah, well...
可我不需要了 你们留着吧
Look, I don't need it. You do, okay?
随你便吧
Suit yourself.
能给我一个吗
Can I have one.
- 给  - 谢谢
- Here.  - Thanks.
你的朋友们看起来不错
Your friends, they seem nice.
让我想起了当年
Kind of reminds me...
发生什么事了
Hey, hey, what's going on?
你已经找到同伴了
You're with your pals. You made it.
你要去哪里
Where will you go?
先去最近的酒吧看看
Nearest bar, for starters.
我已经把你送到了 我的使命完成了
Hey, I got you here. That's all I signed up for.
我还把钱还给你了
I even gave back the money.
你还真是个好人
Such a nice man.
这并不是我想要的
Hey, I never asked for this!
懂吗 这也不是查尔斯想要的
All right? Charles never asked for this.
这也不是卡利班想要的
Caliban never asked for this.
现在他们都躺在了土里
And they are six feet under the ground!
我不知道查尔斯给你灌输了什么
Now, I don't know what Charles put in your head...
反正我不是你心里想的那样 懂吗
but I am not whatever it is you think I am, okay?
我认识你不过一个星期
I only met you, like, a week ago.
你找到了你的丽贝卡 你的黛利拉
You got your Rebecca, your Delilah...
还有其他乱七八糟的人
your blah, blah, blah, whatever.
你想要的都已经得到了
Everything you asked for, you've got it!
而且这样更好
And it is better this way.
因为我总是搞砸
Because I suck at this.
厄运总会降临在我在乎的人身上
Bad shit happens to people I care about.
你懂吗
You understand me?
我不会有事的
Then I'll be fine.
快跑 往山里跑 快跑
Run! Towards the mountains! Run!
快跑 罗比 快跑
Run, Bobby, run!
快 快
Go! Go!
再快点
Move faster!
在他们越过边界前 我们得抓住他们
We need to reach them before they get to the border.
行动
Move out!
我们走 我们走
Let's go, let's go!
跑 快跑
Run! Run!
科尔 约拿 快跑
Corre, Jonah! Run!
尽量呼吸
I want you to breathe.
只是皮肉伤 小子
It's just a flesh wound, baby.
她在这儿
There she is.
抓住她了
We got her.
后退 围住她
Back it up! Contain her.
躲在我身后
Get behind me!
你把药全用上了
You took all the medicine.
药效就快退了
It's wearing off.
到你朋友那儿去
Go to your friends.
去吧
Go.
劳拉
Laura?
我会告诉你时机
You'll know when.
九点方向
Nine o'clock.
绿色液体的药效快没了吧
That green juice is wearin' off, huh?
看来对于老变种人来说药效还真短
You know, for an old mute, it's kind of a short high.
很快你会连爪子都神不出来
Be hard to keep them claws out, soon.
灭了这混蛋 罗根
Waste this dick, Logan!
请住手 豪利特先生
Please stop, Mr. Howlett.
不然我就得下令
I'm gonna have to tell these men
朝孩子们开火了
to fire on these children.
你也不想这样吧
You don't want that.
你也知道血清的药效很快就没了
You can see the effects of the serum are wearing off.
再受伤的话你就活不成了
You will not survive further wounds.
请允许我自我介绍一下
Allow me to introduce myself.
我叫桑德尔·莱斯
I'm Zander Rice.
我想你应在X武器项目中见过我父亲
I believe you knew my father on the Weapon X Program.
没错 就是那个混蛋把毒药注入我体内的
Yeah. He's the asshole who put this poison in me.
对 混蛋之一
Yes, he was one of them.
那他应该已经被我杀了
I think I might have killed him.
你说得没错
I think you're right.
放尊重些 变种人
Why don't you show some respect, mutie?
你眼前的这位可是消灭了所有变种人的人
You're lookin' at the man who wiped out your kind.
我的朋友唐纳德言过其实了
My friend Donald overstates.
他把事情说得过分残忍了
He makes it sound more brutal than intended.
我的目的不是消灭变种人
The goal was not to end mutant kind...
而是掌控他们
but to control it.
我意识到
I realized
我们不该放弃在饮食上的研发
we needn't stop perfecting what we eat and drink.
我们可以用这些产品
That we could use those products
来完善自己
to perfect ourselves.
从饮料到谷物早餐
To distribute gene therapy
在每样东西中
discreetly through everything...
谨慎地进行基因治疗
from sweet drinks to breakfast cereals.
而且成功了
And it worked.
随机出现的变种基因 就像小儿麻痹一样被扼杀了
Random mutancy went the way of polio.
然后我们开始了下一步
We embarked on our next endeavor.
培育你们自己的变种人
Growing mutants of your own.
- 正是  - 世道艰难
- Precisely. - Dangerous times, James.
你不能
You can't...
该你上场了 小子
Showtime, boy!
起来 小子 起来 小子
Get up, boy. Get up, boy!
是他杀的 快起来
He did that. Get up!
劳拉 不
Laura! No!
劳拉
Laura!
饶命
Please.
快走
Go.
走吧
Let's go.
快走
Go.
快 快 快
Go, go, go!
快走 离开这儿 快
Go! Get out of here! Go!
快走 快 快 快
Go. Go, go, go!
快走
Go, go!
Go!
快跑
Run!
不
No!
不 不 不
No, no. No.
带上你的朋友 快跑
Take your friends, and run.
不
No.
他们还会派人来追杀你们
Run. They'll keep coming and coming.
听着 你们不必再战斗了
Listen, you don't have to fight anymore.
走
Go, go.
别成为他们所希望的那样
Don't be what they made you.
劳拉 劳拉
Laura... Laura...
爸爸
Daddy.
原来 死亡是这种感觉
So, this is what it feels like.
不
No!
爸爸
Daddy.
Dad.
人必须忠于自己 乔伊
"A man has to be what he is, Joey.
不能违背自己的本性
"Can't break the mold.
带着杀戮活下去很难
"There's no living with a killing.
这条路没有退路
"There's no going back.
是对是错 你都得背负
"Right or wrong, it's a brand.
直至一生
"A brand that sticks.
现在快回去找你妈妈
"Now you run on home to your mother.
告诉她一切都好
"You tell her everything's all right.
山谷里再也不会有枪声了
"There are no more guns in the valley."
走吧 继续上路
Let's go. We gotta move.
金刚狼3：殊死一战